teamapp.com 2019-06-26

# Team App Privacy Policy

This policy details the kind of personal information that we collect in our business, including through the Website and/or the App (and or Club Apps as defined below), and the ways in which we use it.

In this privacy policy, the terms “we”, “us” and “our” refers to Team Mates Pty Ltd ACN 159 770 537. The term “Website” means the website located at www.teamapp.com and the term “App” means our application for Android, iOS and any other operating systems referred to on our Website.

### Australian Privacy Principles

In Australia, the Australian Privacy Principles contained in the Privacy Act (1988) (Cth govern the handling of personal information. In this privacy policy, the term “personal information” has the meaning in the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth) and includes information about an identifiable individual, including their name, gender, date of birth, address, telephone and fax numbers, email address, drivers’ licence details, credit information and history, banking details, photographs, employment details and if and where applicable, information that constitutes “sensitive information”. “Personal information” includes an opinion about an identifiable individual.

“Sensitive information” is a subset of personal information and includes information about a person’s racial or ethnic origin, health information, political opinions, religious beliefs or affiliations, philosophical beliefs, membership of a professional or trade association or trade union, sexual preferences or practices and criminal record.

### 1\. Collection of personal information

We collect some personal information about individuals. We collect personal information from individuals in circumstances such as the following:

  * When we meet or deal with an individual from an organisation wishing to do business with us;

  * When a person signs up to become a user of the App and/or when a person becomes an administrator (“Club App Administrator”) of a team or a club’s tailored app created using the App (collectively “Club App”);

  * When a user posts content that includes personal information through the App or a Club App;

  * When a user visits the Website or uses the App or a Club App and sends an enquiry through or makes a comment or other post, through an email or via a social media platform;

  * When a user signs up to receive marketing information;

  * When we evaluate job applicants and personnel, which may include collection of details such as employment history and educational qualifications; and

  * Where you are required to pay to purchase goods or services from us or third parties through the Website, the App or a Club App, we (or a financial services provider engaged by us or a third party) will (or that third party) also collect financial information such as credit card information, your mailing address etc.

A significant amount of personal information is primarily collected by Club App Administrators. However, because the information resides on our database we technically “collect” it, although we would not typically access or analyse it. This information could include a range of information as selected by the Club App Administrator, such as names, dates of birth, address, phone number, occupation, employment details, health information, private insurance status, details of ambulance cover, and other information as selected by the Club App Administrator.

### 2\. Other types of information we collect

We collect information on visitors to the Website, including information on which areas of the Website are most often accessed and how long visitors visit those areas.

We collect information from the App and your use of it, including information to assist us to identify the device upon which you use the App, such as your device’s IP address, operating system and your email addresses, location-based data, searches and other information you may input into or access from the App and/or Club App.

We may utilise “cookies” which enable us to monitor traffic patterns and to serve you more efficiently if you revisit the Website. A cookie does not identify you personally but it does identify your computer. You can set your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie and this will provide you with an opportunity to either accept or reject it in each instance. Rejecting cookies may have the effect of limiting your access to parts of the Website.

We may collect information about your computer or device, including where available, your IP address, operating system and browser type, for system administration and to report aggregated information to our advertisers. This is statistical data about our users’ browsing actions and patterns, and does not identify any individual.

### 3\. Use and disclosure of personal information

We may use personal information for the purpose of marketing but only where such use complies with the Australian Privacy Principles.

We use the personal information collected from you for the purpose it was provided or collected, including in the following ways:

  * To enable Club App Administrator(s) to send information and interact with their respective team or club members;

  * To display it when you have posted it to the App or a Club App;

  * For use for the purposes of collection described in section (1) above;

  * To respond to enquiries received from you;

  * To perform authorised financial transactions with you;

  * To enable the provision of location based services to you;

  * To verify your identity and to assist you if you have forgotten any user name or password;

  * To communicate with you and provide you with information (whether by email, post or other means) about our products or services, where you have requested or consented to receiving this from us or where this provision is otherwise permitted under the Australian Privacy Principles;

  * To notify you about changes to the Website, App and/or Club App;  
To ensure that content from the Website, App and or Club App is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your device;

  * To allow you to participate in interactive features of our Website, App and/or Club App when you choose to do so;

  * To receive and address feedback or complaints from you;

  * To protect our legal interests and fulfil our regulatory obligations (if and to the extent necessary); and

  * In other circumstances, with your prior consent.

All users and others with whom we interact have the option to opt-out of receiving email marketing communications from us. If you do not wish to continue to receive electronic marketing communications from us and/or selected third parties you should opt-out by clicking on the “unsubscribe” link in any email communications that we might send you.

Except where otherwise stated by us in this privacy policy or the terms and conditions of our App, we will not, without your consent, sell or otherwise provide your personal information to a third party, or make any other use of your personal information, for any purpose which is not incidental to your use of the Website or the App.

We may disclose personal information, and you consent to us doing so, to our related entities for the purpose for which it was collected or otherwise advised under this policy.

We may disclose or make available personal information, and you consent to us doing so, to third parties who are engaged by us to perform functions or provide products and/or services on our behalf, such as third party hosting service providers and other providers of software products and related services (for the purpose of facilitating the operation of features of the Website and App and to collect and track certain data and information regarding the characteristics and activities of our users), In turn those providers may utilise the services of other third parties to assist in these functions, on the condition that they do not use or disclose any personal information for extraneous purposes. In addition we may disclose or make available some personal information to financial services providers processing credit cards and our agents, business partners, joint venture entities or contractors, for the purpose of distributing materials that you have consented to receive. We may also need to disclose personal information if required to conduct any investigation into you or your activities, if for example there is reason to believe that you have committed a breach of our Website or App terms and conditions. We may also disclose such information as required or permitted by any law.

We may make some of your details or personal information available to third parties for advertising purposes. We may use and/or disclose limited information such as age, gender and location details in order to provide targeted advertising to users. This may involve using passing limited information to ad-servers, such as details of age, gender and sports played.

If you request us not to use personal information in a particular manner at all, we will adopt reasonable measures to observe your request, but you acknowledge that use of the Website, App and/or Club App may involve some use of your personal information and that following your request, we may still use or disclose that information if:

  * you do not provide us with adequate time to address your request;

  * we subsequently notify you of the intended use or disclosure and you do not object to that use or disclosure;

  * we believe that the use or disclosure is reasonably necessary to assist a law enforcement agency or an agency responsible for government or public security in the performance of their functions;

  * you continue to use the App or Website;

  * you do not uninstall our App; or

  * we are required by law to disclose the information.

Unless in using the Website or App you expressly or impliedly agree to make certain information available and able to be used and/or disclosed by use, all personal information which we collect is kept confidential to the best of our ability, subject to the terms of the App you use and this privacy policy. You will appreciate, however, that we cannot guarantee the security of transmission as there are always risks associated with transmitting information across the Internet.

In addition, our employees, contractors and other product/service providers who provide services related to our Website and App are obliged to respect the confidentiality of any personal information held by us.   
Personal information which we collect may be aggregated for analysis but, except in circumstances where you expressly or impliedly indicate that you wish to make the information available to others and to identify you, we will use best endeavours to ensure that individuals remain unidentified.

### 5\. How Google uses data when you use the App

For information as to how Google uses data as a consequence of use of the App, please see the following on Google’s site: How Google uses data when you use our partners’ sites or apps.

Please note also that we may, in connection with Google Platform Products that we use, collect process or disclose information that identifies or can be used to an infer an end user’s precise geographic location, such as GPS, wifi or cell tower data. We will only send such information to Google in an encrypted state or via an encrypted channel.

### 6\. Sharing with businesses, individuals and clubs we do not control

The App (and Club Apps) by their nature mean that other third party businesses, individuals and clubs may obtain personal information from you, in respect of which we cannot exercise significant practical control. While we endeavour to have those third parties adhere to terms and conditions that require them to respect privacy of personal information, we cannot guarantee that they will do so and accept no liability in the event of a breach.

### 7\. Overseas disclosure

We may make some personal information available to businesses located outside Australia, for the purposes of those businesses providing hosting services and/or providing goods/services that enable the App and Website to function and for us to provide various features and track certain data and information. Those third party service providers agree with us that they will not to use or disclose the personal information for unrelated or extraneous purposes. These service providers are typically located in the United States of America. Apart from these uses we do not otherwise disclose information outside Australia.

### 8\. Security of personal information

We hold personal information in our own secure databases.

We take all reasonable steps to protect your personal information, including internal and external security, restricting access to personal information to those who have a need to know and maintain technological products to prevent unauthorised computer access and regularly reviewing our technology to maintain security.

We treat website and credit card security seriously and endeavour to provide a secure, safe platform through which to conduct transactions (if any).

### 9\. Questions, concerns and access to your personal information

You are entitled to have access to any personal information relating to you which you have previously supplied to us. To obtain a copy of the personal information we hold at you please write to us using the contact details provided below.

### 10\. Other

If at any time you provide or disclose personal information about someone other than yourself, you must ensure and you warrant that you have that person’s consent to provide such information for the purpose specified.

While this website and the App are not intended to target minors, we consider it is the responsibility of parents to monitor their children’s use of our Website and Apps.

In the event that our business is ever sold, acquired, merged, liquidated, reorganised or otherwise transferred, we reserve the right to transfer to the extent permissible at law, our user databases, together with any personal information and non-personal information contained therein to a third party acquiring the assets.

### 11\. Changes to and limitations of this policy

We reserve the right to make changes to this policy. Such changes will be updated on the Website and within the App following the making of such changes.

The Website and App may provide links to other third party sites as a service to our users. Our privacy policy described here does not apply to those sites. Please ensure that you review and agree with the terms and conditions and privacy policy of any linked website before providing any personal information.

### 12\. Contact us

If you wish to make an inquiry regarding any personal information relating to you which may be in our possession, contact:

The Privacy Officer  
Team Mates Pty Ltd   
ACN 159 770 537   
370 Darebin Rd  
Thornbury VIC 3071  
AUSTRALIA

or privacy@teamapp.com
